{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"David Yates","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows – Part 2?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ivan Turgenev","incorrectAnswers":["Leo Tolstoy","Henryk Sienkiewicz","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Poems in Prose'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Mictlantecuhtli","incorrectAnswers":["Tlaloc","Quetzalcoatl","Huitzilopochtli"],"question":"What is the name of the Aztec god of death?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Mariah Carey","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Madonna"],"question":"Which American singer and songwriter released the song 'All I Want for Christmas Is You'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Reindeer","incorrectAnswers":["Horses","Buffalo","Alpacas"],"question":"Which animal is central to the nomadic herding economy of the Sami people?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1989","incorrectAnswers":["1977","1981","1985"],"question":"Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Siddhartha Gautama ","incorrectAnswers":["Simon Bolivar","Confucius","Bahadur Shah"],"question":"Who was the founder of Buddhism?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"It’s the sense of touch. In any real city, you walk, you know? You brush past people, people bump into you. In L.A., nobody touches you. We’re always behind this metal and glass. I think we miss that touch so much, that we crash into each other, just so we can feel something.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"May the Force be with you.\"","\"Here's looking at you, kid.\"","\"What is this? A center for ants? How can we be expected to teach children to learn how to read…if they can’t even fit inside the building?\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Crash'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"fish","incorrectAnswers":["a variant of physiognomy","oceans","the Islam"],"question":"What is Ichthyology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Water","incorrectAnswers":["Salt","Foliage","Human Settlement"],"question":"Over 75% of the Earth's surface is covered by some form of _____.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Bronze Age","incorrectAnswers":["The Stone Age","The Steel Age","The Wooden Age"],"question":"What age preceded the Iron Age?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Dido","incorrectAnswers":["Nelly Furtado","Mariah Carey","Norah Jones"],"question":"Which female singer dueted with Eminem on the 2000 hit 'Stan'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Vienna","incorrectAnswers":["Budapest","Berlin","Prague"],"question":"Which European City Did Ultravox Sing About?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Japanese-Canadians","incorrectAnswers":["African-Canadians","Indigenous Canadians","European-Canadians"],"question":"Starting in February 1942, Canada began moving 21,000 people of what background to internment camps?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"drugs","incorrectAnswers":["the scientific study of muscles","animal diseases","museum management"],"question":"What is Pharmacology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"206","incorrectAnswers":["310","233","280"],"question":"How Many Bones Are There In The Adult Human Body?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Parsley","incorrectAnswers":["Basil","Oregano","Thyme"],"question":"Which herb is often used as a garnish and comes in curly-leaf and flat-leaf varieties?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ethiopia","incorrectAnswers":["Guinea","Kosovo","Yemen"],"question":"Addis Ababa is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Xenon","incorrectAnswers":["Halogen","Neon","Radon"],"question":"What chemical element gets is name from the greek word meaning 'stranger'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A novice","incorrectAnswers":["A friar","A cleric","A nun"],"question":"What is the term for a person who has joined a Catholic religious order, but has not yet taken vows, originating from the Latin for 'new'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Rugby","Golf","Polo"],"question":"Which sport keeps track of the score with the words \"deuce\" and \"advantage\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["White","Blue","Purple"],"question":"What is the traditional color associated with Valentine's Day?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pieter Bruegel the Elder","incorrectAnswers":["Caravaggio","Jackson Pollock","Gustave Courbet"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Tower of Babel\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Finland","incorrectAnswers":["Poland","Lithuania","Latvia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Sweden?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Erik The Red ","incorrectAnswers":["Ragnar Lothbrok","Leif Erikson","Beowulf"],"question":"Which Viking Chief, Banished From Iceland, Founded The Norse Colonies On Greenland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Austroasiatic","Kra–Dai","Turkic"],"question":"The language 'Nepali' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"An order of monks ","incorrectAnswers":["An Italian Town","A type of monkey","A legendary musician"],"question":"A Cappuccino Coffee Is Named After What?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Irish Coffee ","incorrectAnswers":["Black Velvet","Espresso Martini","Black Russian"],"question":"Whiskey, hot coffee, and whipped cream make up which type of drink","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Julia Roberts","incorrectAnswers":["Meryl Streep","Sandra Bullock","Anne Hathaway"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Erin Brockovich and Ocean's Eleven?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jaye Davidson","incorrectAnswers":["Dennis Hopper","Sean Penn","Samuel L. Jackson"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Dil in The Crying Game?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Reese Witherspoon","incorrectAnswers":["Kristin Scott Thomas","Naomi Watts","Penélope Cruz"],"question":"Which actress has starred in both Walk the Line and Cruel Intentions?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"George Washington","incorrectAnswers":["John Adams","Abraham Lincoln","Thomas Jefferson"],"question":"Who Was The First President Of The United States?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Snails ","incorrectAnswers":["Frogs","Insects","Turtles"],"question":"What Are Escargots?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Peru","incorrectAnswers":["Niger","Zimbabwe","India"],"question":"Quechua is a language spoken in which of these countries?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Reservoir Dogs","incorrectAnswers":["Pulp Fiction","Jackie Brown","Kill Bill"],"question":"In which film did Steve Buscemi play a character called \"Mr. Pink\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["Spain","France","Taiwan"],"question":"Which country is associated with the drink rakı?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Allure","incorrectAnswers":["Elle","Vogue","InStyle"],"question":"Which magazine name applies to a charismatic person and claims to be \"The Beauty Expert\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"H. Rider Haggard","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Jin Yong","Charles Darwin"],"question":"Which author wrote 'King Solomon's Mines'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Honolulu","incorrectAnswers":["Los Angeles","New York City","Tokyo"],"question":"Which city is home to ALA Moana, also known as \"the world's largest open-air shopping center\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Cate Blanchett","incorrectAnswers":["Laura Linney","Virginia Madsen","Sophie Okonedo"],"question":"Who won the 2004 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Katharine Hepburn in The Aviator?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Warsaw","incorrectAnswers":["Krakow","Poznan","Lodz"],"question":"What is the capital of Poland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Jarlsberg","incorrectAnswers":["Gouda","Cheddar","Brie"],"question":"Which of these is a Norwegian cheese with undertones of nuts?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Your Mileage May Vary","incorrectAnswers":["You're Meeting My Villain","You Must Meet Voters","You Make Me Vomit"],"question":"On internet chats, what do the letters 'YMMV' mean?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cricket","incorrectAnswers":["Rugby","Baseball","Swimming"],"question":"Which sport is played at The ICC World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Who","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Travis","Spandau Ballet"],"question":"Which band was co-founded by 'Pete Townshend'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Saccharide","incorrectAnswers":["Glucose","Fructose","Lipid"],"question":"What is another word for carbohydrate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"George Lazenby","incorrectAnswers":["Roger Moore","Pierce Brosnan","Sean Connery"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in On Her Majesty's Secret Service?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["Europe","Asia","South America"],"question":"On which continent was the historical country of Rhodesia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Insulin","incorrectAnswers":["Estrogen","Keratin","Adrenaline"],"question":"What Hormone Controls The Supply Of Sugar From The Blood To The Muscles?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Butter ","incorrectAnswers":["Cheese","Milk","Cream"],"question":"Along with wine vinegar and egg yolk, what other ingredient would you find in hollandaise sauce?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Snowy","incorrectAnswers":["Foxy","Pal","Rover"],"question":"What is the name of the white fox terrier owned by boy explorer Tintin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"J.K. Simmons","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Duvall","Ethan Hawke","Edward Norton"],"question":"Who won the 2014 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor for playing the role of Fletcher in Whiplash?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mozambique","incorrectAnswers":["Burkina Faso","Sao Tome and Principe","Micronesia"],"question":"Maputo is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Senegal","incorrectAnswers":["The Gambia","Guinea-Bissau","Guinea"],"question":"Dakar is the capital of ______?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"New York Islanders","incorrectAnswers":["New York Sharks","New York Predators","New York Real"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in New York?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'She Loves You'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mount St. Helens","incorrectAnswers":["Mount Fuji","Mount Vesuvius","Mount Kilimanjaro"],"question":"Which volcano's 1980 eruption caused the city of Spokane to be plunged into darkness due to the ash?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Tiercel","incorrectAnswers":["A Macho","A Cock","A Billy"],"question":"What is the word for a male eagle?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pakistan","incorrectAnswers":["Iran","Sri Lanka","Nepal"],"question":"Which country is located between Afghanistan and India?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Mumtaj Mahal","incorrectAnswers":["Taj Bodhi","Lugah Taj","Mahal Mahore"],"question":"Who was the Taj Mahal built in memory of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"James Fenimore Cooper","incorrectAnswers":["Edgar Rice Burroughs","Jack London","Edgar Allan Poe"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Last of the Mohicans'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hydrogen","incorrectAnswers":["Helium","Oxygen","Nitrogen"],"question":"What is the most common element in the universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Lesotho is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"All Born On Christmas Day","incorrectAnswers":["All British Nobility","All Died By Drowning","All Related To Each Other (by blood)"],"question":"What Connects Kenny Everett, Annie Lennox, And Sir Isaac Newton?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Who released the studio album 'Invincible'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tunisia","incorrectAnswers":["Morocco","Kenya","Sudan"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Tunis?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Aristotle","incorrectAnswers":["Plato","Socrates","Diogenes"],"question":"Who taught Alexander the Great? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Another Brick in the Wall'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"George Washington","incorrectAnswers":["Abraham Lincoln","Gerald Ford","John Tyler"],"question":"Which influential US president was a leader of the forces during American Revolution?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Charles I","incorrectAnswers":["James I","James II","Edward I"],"question":"Who was the monarch of England during the time period 1625-1649?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Pup","incorrectAnswers":["A Caterpillar","A Cygnet","A Calf"],"question":"What is a baby seal known as?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Juneau","incorrectAnswers":["Anchorage","Fairbanks","Ketchikan"],"question":"What is the capital city of Alaska?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Renaissance","incorrectAnswers":["Industrial Revolution","Classical Period","Age of Discovery"],"question":"What is the name given to the period of European history between the Middle Ages and modernity?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Chicago Bears","incorrectAnswers":["Chicago Falcons","Chicago Marlins","Chicago Timbers"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Chicago?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Joseph Heller","incorrectAnswers":["Vladimir Nabokov","Kurt Vonnegut","Cassandra Clare"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Catch-22'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Detroit Pistons","incorrectAnswers":["Detroit Dolphins","Detroit Nuggets","Detroit Real"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Detroit?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Football","incorrectAnswers":["Skiing","Golf","Swimming"],"question":"With which sport is Bill Shankly associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["France","Hungary","Russia"],"question":"Which country did Angela Merkel lead from 2005 to 2021?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Giant Kelp","incorrectAnswers":["Giant Algae","Giant Kombu","Giant Sea Lettuce"],"question":"What is the largest seaweed?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Whiffler","incorrectAnswers":["Firman","Salopettes","Donkey Engine"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'somebody who walks in front of you through a crowd'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Unforgiven","incorrectAnswers":["Inception","Das Boot","Hacksaw Ridge"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A retired gunslinger takes on one last job, with the help of his old partner and a young man.'","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Easter Island","incorrectAnswers":["Hawaii","Madagascar","Cuba"],"question":"The Rongorongo,  writing system is found on which remote island?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Kra–Dai","incorrectAnswers":["Sino-Tibetan","Austroasiatic","Afroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Thai' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"South Korea","incorrectAnswers":["Vanuatu","Peru","Sweden"],"question":"Seoul is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Seth Rogen","incorrectAnswers":["Russell Crowe","Jean-Claude Van Damme","Pierce Brosnan"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Arrested Development and Donnie Darko?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band (1970-) released the studio album 'News of the World'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Paraguay","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","Jamaica","Mexico"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Asuncion?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bilbao","incorrectAnswers":["Dublin","Stuttgart","Cologne"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Spain?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Halfpace","incorrectAnswers":["Yarborough","Erf","Bobsy-die"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a platform of a staircase where the stair turns back in exactly the reverse direction of the lower flight'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Photocopying","incorrectAnswers":["Lock picking","Deep fat frying","Radiography"],"question":"In 1937 Chester Carlson invented a process called Xerography. What do we call it today?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'We Can Work It Out'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Vin Diesel","incorrectAnswers":["Dwayne Johnson","Jason Statham","Chris Hemsworth"],"question":"In 2013, which actor reprised his role as the character 'Riddick'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Lapidary","incorrectAnswers":["Byzantine","Iconography","Philately"],"question":"What is the term for the polishing and cutting of stones and gems?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Pianist","incorrectAnswers":["Unforgiven","Gandhi","The Terminator"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A Polish Jew struggles to survive the destruction of the Warsaw ghetto of World War II.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Golden Fleece","incorrectAnswers":["The Trident of Poseidon","The Helm of Darkness","The Scepter of the Gods"],"question":"In Greek mythology, what did Jason steal from his Uncle Pelias?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Louis Pasteur","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Faraday","Jean-Jacques Rousseau","Enrico Fermi"],"question":"Which scientist developed a cure for rabies and other infectious diseases?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Cats Eye","incorrectAnswers":["Traffic Light","Airbag","Crumple Zone"],"question":"What Road Safety Device Was Invented By Percy Shaw In 1943? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Wings","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","The Chemical Brothers"],"question":"Which British–American rock band led by Paul McCartney released the album 'Band on the Run'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Peter the Great","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Jacques Rousseau","Napoleon","Rasputin"],"question":"Which influential historical person was a Russian Emperor?","difficulty":"easy"},